RESUME

Name : Ishimdar Ahamad

Qualification: B.Tech(Information Technology)

Email id : ahamadishimdar@gmail.com

Mobile No : (91) 8860792664

Address: A-101, Sector-52, Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

9+ years of Industry experience in providing User Interface & User Experience design with HTML5, CSS3, BootStrap, JavaScript and ReactJs & Redux with Jest Development with most usable enterprise-wide applications. To secure an intriguing and challenging job in the top of a league organization, where I can use my knowledge and skills to lead the organization as well as my career to the top.

WORKING EXPERIENCE:

- Currently working as MODULE LEAD (FRONT END Development) in LTIMindtree,
 Noida from August 2022 to till date.
- Worked as a Front-end Developer with ReactJS & Redux in FlowerAura, Gurugram from October 2018 to July 2022.
- Worked as a Product Engineer with AngularJS in Qilo Technolgies Pvt. Ltd. Noida from April 2016 to October 2018.
- Worked as a UI Developer with JQuery in Qlique Mediatech Pvt. Ltd. Noida from August 2014 to April 2016.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:

- B.Tech in Information Technology in May 2011 from I.T.M Gida, Gorakhpur with 62%
- Passed 10+2 in May 2007 from P.M.I.C, Azamgarh with 61%.
- Passed 10th in May 2005 from P.M.I.C, Azamgarh with 60%.

SKILLS:

Operating SystemsWindows XP, Windows 7, Windows 10Web TechnologiesHTML5, CSS3, SASS, Javascript, JSON

Frameworks : ReactJS, Redux, Javascript, Bootstrap, jQuery, AngularJS, RestAPI

Script Editors : Dreamweaver, jetbrains webstorm, Visual Studio Code

Tools : Chrome develop tool, Photoshop, CI/CD Process, DevOps

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Project #1:

Title: DL-FP-Dramix Calculator

Client: Bekart

Role: UI with responsive & Senior Front-end Developer with ReactJS, Redux and helped team to

achieved this goal. **IDE:** VS Code

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, ReactJs, Redux, Bootstrap, AEM

Project Description: Bekart-Dramix Calculator is a B2C tool to design sustainable steel fibre floors. Based on different parameters load selection, tool selection, input selection etc. It will calculate the final result to show how much material is required. This project was based on AEM 6.5(Service pack 12) with React. Also, it has a Mulesoft integration and Azure ADB2C authentication for manging the users.

Environment: Visual Studio Code, Material UI, FormIk

Project #2:

Title: Pharma Intelligence - TrialScope

Client: Informa

Role: UI & Senior Front-end Developer with ReactJS, Redux, CI/CD Process & DevOps

IDE: VS Code

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, ReactJs, Redux, Formik, Material UI

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Build enhancements (including new product features) and resolve bugs. Take complete
 ownership of export feature module used devextrem.
- Work with senior members across multiple teams, Experience working in Scrum/Agile development environment. Agile mindset, ability to iterate, take a risk and evolve.

Environment: Visual Studio Code, Material UI, FormIk

Project #3:

Title: Floweraura **Client:** floweraura

Role: UI & Front-end Developer with ReactJS, Redux, CI/CD Process & DevOps

IDE: VS Code

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, ReactJs, Redux

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Build enhancements (including new product features) and resolve bugs. Take complete ownership of Features and handle CI & CD process.
- Work with senior members across multiple teams, Experience working in Scrum/Agile development environment. Agile mindset, ability to iterate, take a risk and evolve.
- Implementing client-side design patterns using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, React with Redux and JavaScript. Solving complex issues related to browser and network performance, cross-browser compatibility, client-side scaling, data modeling, usability, and testability.

Environment: Adobe Photoshop, Dreamweaver, Visual Studio Code, Jenkins, CI/CD process.

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Volunteered in Tech N Gen (CONVOCATION 2011of ITM).
- Represented IT Branch for the I.H.L(intra hostel League) held in ITM and won Gold medal for two successive years (2009-10, 20010-11).
- Awarded as the Best Fielder in a cricket match conducted by I.H.L.

HOBBIES:

- Playing any Sport
- Learning new thing for my carrier

PERSONAL DETAILS:

DOB : 26 November 1990

Sex : Male
Marital Status : Married

Father's Name : Subhan Ahamad
Permanent Address : Azamgarh, U.P.
Languages Known : English, Hindi, Urdu
Correspondence Add : Noida Sector - 34,U.P.

I hereby	declare	that	the	above	written	particulars	are	true	to	the	best	of	my	knowledge	and
belief.															

\boldsymbol{L}	12	$r_{\mathcal{O}}$	
	ıu	u	

Date: (Ishimdar Ahamad)